[MUSIC]
&gt;&gt; Kubernetes was founded almost
seven years ago my guess,
Kubernetes几乎成立了
我猜七年前，
depending on when you
start the clock when it
取决于当你开始计时
publicly released or when
development started.
它何时公开发布或何时开始开发。
It was the three of us,
是我们三个人
Joe Beda, Craig McLuckie, and myself.
Honestly, we were influenced
by some internal systems.
老实说，我们受到了一些内部系统的影响。
A system called Borg at Google
that we'd been using at the time,
我们当时一直在使用的Google Borg系统，
as well as our own experience
with people trying to adopt
Cloud and the challenges
of people adopting Cloud.
以及我们自己与尝试采用云计算的人们的经验，以及采用云计算的人们所面临的挑战。
It was hard, it's too hard, right?
很难，很难，对吗？
Docker came along honestly.
Docker诚实地出现了。
I think without Docker,
we couldn't have done it.
我想没有Docker，我们就不可能做到这一点。
All right, so Docker lit this fire,
好的，所以Docker点燃了这一切，
but we had all this experience
about where they should go.
但是我们对他们应该去哪里有所有的经验。
So we took the enthusiasm around
containers that Docker
managed to generate up.
所以我们对 Docker 生成的容器产生了热情。
So Kubernetes is an orchestrator
for helping you with
application development.
因此Kubernetes是帮助您进行应用程序开发的协调器。
When you think about what it takes
to deploy an application up to
the Cloud or even to an on-premise
collection of machines.
You have to package
up that application.
当您考虑如何将应用程序部署到云端，甚至部署到本地计算机集合时。
You have to distribute it,
你必须分发
you have to keep it running,
and you have load balance traffic
between the various pieces
of the application.
您必须分发它，必须使其运行，并且必须在应用程序的各个部分之间进行负载平衡流量。
Then obviously in an API
to introspective and find
out what's going on.
然后显然可以使用API进行内省并找出正在发生的情况。
Before Kubernetes there were a
few systems bits and pieces,
在 Kubernetes 之前有一些零碎的系统，
but Kubernetes just really
mainstreamed the idea of
this distributed systems
application environment
for building and constructing
distributed systems that span
across a bunch of machines.
但是 Kubernetes 才真正将这种分布式系统应用程序环境的思想主流化，以构建和构建跨越一堆机器的分布式系统。
I think Kubernetes
really succeeded because
of our focus on
community and ecosystem.
So I think technologically
obviously has to work.
But I think that building
this really honestly
amazing community
of people who supported each other,
who helped build docs,
who helped build tutorials,
who went and talked
about it in conferences.
Then an ecosystem of
companies that were
betting their whole company on it.
Startups that are saying like, well,
the prerequisite for using
my monitoring software is that
you have a Kubernetes cluster,
that formed a really virtuous cycle.
I think the other thing
is that it's a layer in
the stack that is at some
level supposed to disappear.
So once it became popular enough,
everyone's was like, okay,
that decision has been
made, let's move on.
All right, and so there's
a certain amount of
value for the broader ecosystem
and having a single solution.
Container is one of
those words were I think
it means different things
to different people,
or has a really broad
set of meanings.
I think fundamentally,
it's about taking an
application and packaging it.
So building of binary representation
of all the different pieces that you
need for your application,
the software,
the configuration files, whatever,
just having a protocol for
distributing that application
around the world.
Then once it starts
running on a machine,
having a isolated playground for
that application to
run so that it can't
interfere with other applications
on the same machine.
So I think those are
the three pillars
of what became known as containers.
How do I take everything
and package it?
So it's exactly the same on my
laptop as it is out in the Cloud.
How do I distribute it around
the world really easily?
Then once it's running, how
can I have an environment
where if I have a bug
in one component,
it doesn't affect another component?
Those pieces are what makes up
what it means to be a container.
Although different people
have different answers.
Well, I'm an open source fundamentally
means that the source code
for your project is available
under an open source license.
So there's a consortium that
defines what it means
to be open source,
has to do with different
open source licenses
exist that have different kinds of
restrictions on what
you can do with it.
If you make changes, if you
have to publish those changes.
But fundamentally, from
my perspective of what it
really means is coming
together as a community to
build software in the open.
So it's not Microsoft
building software,
or Apple building software,
or VMware building software,
it's all of us coming
together in a global project.
It's Kubernetes building
software as a project out on
GitHub that makes up the open source.
For me, that was really important.
It's not just about the license,
it's not just about the
source being out there,
but it's about the community that
comes together to build the software.
But I think when we're
talking about Cloud Native,
one of the things that
we're thinking about is
API-driven development.
So you're creating stuff with an API.
You're not logging into a
machine running commands,
you're declaring a state
usually these days in some
text file like a YAML file.
Then you're applying that state
to the world and you're letting
some other system take responsibility
for making reality match up
with your declared state.
So this has been called
Infrastructure as code
or a bunch of other kind of
buds words associated with it.
I think the other
part of Cloud Native
is this idea of elastic scale, right?
That I can immediately get
more resources if I need them,
I can immediately
throw away resources.
I think of Cloud is
being a better version
of an online computer retailer
where like used to be,
you can get a computer in a day and
you had to go through
some return policy.
Well, with Cloud you can get it in
a few seconds and you can
give it back and immediately.
So run it for two minutes,
put it away, don't pay
for it ever again.
I think that's a
fundamental characteristic
of what it means to be Cloud
Native because they're now
development patterns that assume
that I can create a complete
copy of my infrastructure and
then throw away my old copy without
any real effect on me in terms
of price or anything else.
That's what it means for
me to be Cloud Native.
Well, people keep saying the
future of Kubernetes is boring.
Like it's supposed
to be disappearing.
It keeps sort of not disappearing.
But I keep thinking it's
going to disappear.
That's because it's present in
every major public
Cloud at this point.
It's become something that
people just expect to be there.
So people are really focused
on what do you build above it.
I think one of the decisions
early on that we made those
really foresightful was to
make it very extensible.
So that people could
add on new components.
So people could make it their own.
I think that's the future is the
stuff that gets built on top.
As more developer tooling and as
more experiences get
built on top, I think,
I hope that the underlying
Kubernetes bits is kind of
fade, like X86 fades.
Where nobody really
talks about like what's
the processor architecture
instruction set that you're running?
It's there, obviously it's important,
but it's not part of what you
think about on the day to day.
I hope that's the future
for Kubernetes as well
because there's so much
more that we need to build.